翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）
So let's try doing something a little more complicated.
接下来让我们做一些更复杂的事情
I'm going to write a program over here called Hello numbers dot py.
我要在这写一个程序，叫 hellonumbers.py
What it's going to do is it's going to print all the numbers between 0 and 10.
它将打印0到10之间的所有数字
So while x is less than 10.
所以当 x 小于10时
x equals x plus 1.
x = x + 1
And we'll also print out x.
同时打印 x
We run this.
运行代码
Here they are-- 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9.
结果在这里...0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9
Let's try writing that same program in Java.
让我们尝试用 Java 编写同样的程序
So we're going to call this Hello numbers dot Java.
我们把这个程序叫做 HelloNumbers.java
And what I'm going to do is name my class Hello numbers,
首先要将类命名为 HelloNumbers
and I'll put my code here.
代码放在这里
Now you notice in my text editor I had some funny thing that happened more like all that stuff popped up at once.
你可能注意到我的编辑器中发生了有趣的事情，这些东西一下子全冒出来
That's a little trick in this text editor I'm using.
这是我正在使用编辑器中的一个小技巧
If you're curious, there will be a link in the book that will show you how to do that.
书中有一个链接会解答你的疑惑
But it's not necessary for this class.
但是课上就不介绍了
And in fact, starting next week, we're going to encourage you to use not a text editor to use something called an IDE.
事实上从下周开始，我们将鼓励你们丢弃文本编辑器，使用一种叫做 IDE 的东西
We'll talk about that later.
我们稍后再谈这个
So here we have a class called Hello numbers.
这里我们创建了一个叫 HelloNumbers 的类
And in Java, what I'm going to do is I'm just going to start naively and I'm going to try and guess how it works.
我们猜猜看在 Java 中用最单纯的方式会有什么结果
So I might say, while x is less than 10,
先写 while (x < 10)
we'll add a curly braces to delimit the beginning and end.
我们将添加一个大括号来分隔开头和结尾
Because that's what we do in Java.
因为 Java 中需要这样做
Then I'll say, system doc out dot print line x.
然后写 System.out.println(x)
And then I'll say x equals x plus 1.
再写 x = x + 1
So I try running this code over here, I get error,
运行代码得到一个错误
cannot find symbol x.
找不到符号 x
Now while you might originally be tempted to say OK, well, maybe it's too small.
可能你会想：“嗯，是字体太小了”
Just increase the font size.
增大字体就行了
You'll see that doesn't work.
你会发现这没用的
You also can't do things like this,
同时这样也不可以
you know, like help the compiler find the symbol.
比如帮编译器找到符号
That's just going to confuse it even more.
这只会让它更加混乱
Actually, what it is trying to tell you is that you should be declaring your variable.
实际上，编译器告诉你应该定义变量
That's something we need to do in Java.
这是 Java 中必须做的事情
I'm not sure if I got that size right.
不知道这个大小合不合适
Close enough.
应该差不多
So what it's saying is before a variable could be used,
它说的是，在使用变量之前
you have to specify that it exists.
必须声明它的存在
So I could do that by saying, for example, int x.
所以我可以这样做，比如 int x
So this is a variable declaration that says one,
这是一个定义变量的语句
x exists and two, it's an integer.
一是 x 存在，二是 x 是一个整型
So if I now run this code, I get the same behavior out of my Java program.
这样 Java 中的代码会做出相同的事情
And just kind of a minor seeming thing,
这好像是个小事
but it ends up having really big consequences for the way that we're going to write code in Java.
但最终对我们 Java 编写代码的方式产生了很大影响
So just to show you a shorthand, you can also if you want just write out int x equals 0.
还有一种简写的方法，也可以写作 int x = 0
So that's all in one line.
写在一行内
So in other words you're declaring and setting the variable at the same time.
你就同时定义和设置了变量
And that'll work fine.
这样就可以运行了
It's all the same.
完全一样
So there are some big differences between Java and Python in terms of how variables work.
因此，Java 和 Python 在变量方面有很大的不同
With Python or other languages that are not so-called statically typed languages,
对于 Python 这种非静态语言
you can create variables willy nilly.
你可以随意创建变量
You can put whatever you want in them.
你可以在变量里放任何东西
Know I can decide later that x is actually horse.
可以在后面把它设成 horse
Run it, and you'll get 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, horse.
运行它，你会得到0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 horse
But if try and pull a similar trick in Java, it won't work so well.
但是这种技巧在 Java 中并不适用
In this case, I get error, string cannot be converted to int.
在这种情况下我得到错误，字符串不能转换为整型
And even if you try and do something like this, now it'll yell at you and say, well x is already defined.
即使这样修改，它也会报“x 已经定义”的错误
So in Java, variables have a specific type.
Java 中变量有明确的类型
And those types can never change.
这些类型永远不会改变
And that's going to have really big consequences in that when we're looking at our programs,
这将会对我们的程序产生巨大影响
especially when we start talking about functions, you'll know exactly what's in each type of variable
特别是当我们讨论函数时，你将确切了解每种类型的变量
and what's more the compiler will actually check and make sure all of the types are good before you even run the program.
另外，编译器会在运行程序前检查确保每种变量的类型正确
So let's make some notes.
让我们做些笔记
Before Java variables can be used they must be declared.
使用 Java 变量前要先定义
Java variables must have a specific type.
Java 变量必须具有明确的类型
Java variable types can never change.
Java 变量类型永远不能更改
Hello, Roy.
你好，Roy
All right. Fun stuff.
有趣的家伙
Now type errors are not unique to Java.
类型错误并不是 Java 独有的
They also exist in languages like Python.
它们也存在于 Python 等语言中
For example, in Python, it is not valid to say print 5 plus horse.
例如在 Python 中，打印5 + "horse"是无效的
And if you try running this Python program,
运行这个 Python 程序
you'll get 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, horse.
你会得到0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 horse
And then we see an error appear.
然后会看到一个错误
So it's something that you can't do in Python.
所以在 Python 中你不能这样做
But what's interesting about Java is that when we try and run code that has a type error,
但 Java 有趣的是，当我们尝试运行有类型错误的代码时
you'll notice that there's a big difference.
你会注意到有很大区别
This code actually prints out a bunch of stuff before getting to the type error,
在遇到类型错误之前，这段代码实际上会打印出一堆内容
whereas in Java, we get error incompatible types and the program doesn't even run.
而在 Java 中，类型不兼容错误导致程序甚至无法运行
So what's interesting about Java's typing system is that types are verified before the code even runs.
因此 Java 类型系统的有趣之处在于，在代码运行前验证类型
And that's a big difference between Java and Python.
这是 Java 和 Python 之间的一个很大的区别
Here, this code basically gets a certificate of correctness in terms of types before the code runs.
Java 代码在运行前就要确保类型方面的正确
And what that means is that one, that's fewer bugs that your end users are going to run into, two, makes it easier for you to debug.
这意味着，一是最终会遇到更少的错误，二是让你更容易调试
And then a third aspect of static types that's really nice is that while you're working with your code,
第三个好处是当你使用代码时
you know what everything should be,
你对它们了如指掌
that x should always be an integer.
x 应该始终是一个整型
And we'll see when we get to functions and especially in the coming weeks why that's such an amazing and important piece of the Java language.
接下来几周谈论函数时，你会发现 Java 这部分特性带来的巨大帮助
翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）